<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PINGA lab</title><link href="http://pinga-lab.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pinga-lab.github.io/feeds/melo-f-f-v-c-f-barbosa-l-uieda-v-c-oliveira-jr-and-j-b-c-silva.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pinga-lab.github.io/</id><updated>2013-01-12T00:00:00-02:00</updated><entry><title>Estimating the nature and the horizontal and vertical positions of 3D magnetic sources using Euler deconvolution</title><link href="http://pinga-lab.github.io/papers/paper-euler-plateau-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-12T00:00:00-02:00</updated><author><name>Melo, F. F., V. C. F. Barbosa, L. Uieda, V. C. Oliveira Jr, and J. B. C. Silva</name></author><id>tag:pinga-lab.github.io,2013-01-12:papers/paper-euler-plateau-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have developed a new method that drastically reduces the number of the
source location estimates in Euler deconvolution to only one per anomaly. Our
method employs the analytical estimators of the base level and of the
horizontal and vertical source positions in Euler deconvolution as a function
of the x- and y-coordinates of the observations. By assuming any tentative
structural index (defining the geometry of the sources), our method
automatically locates plateaus, on the maps of the horizontal coordinate
estimates, indicating consistent estimates that are very close to the true
corresponding coordinates. These plateaus are located in the neighborhood of
the highest values of the anomaly and show a contrasting behavior with those
estimates that form inclined planes at the anomaly borders. The plateaus are
automatically located on the maps of the horizontal coordinate estimates by
fitting a first-degree polynomial to these estimates in a moving-window scheme
spanning all estimates. The positions where the angular coefficient estimates
are closest to zero identify the plateaus of the horizontal coordinate
estimates. The sample means of these horizontal coordinate estimates are the
best horizontal location estimates. After mapping each plateau, our method
takes as the best structural index the one that yields the minimum correlation
between the total-field anomaly and the estimated base level over each plateau.
By using the estimated structural index for each plateau, our approach extracts
the vertical coordinate estimates over the corresponding plateau. The sample
means of these estimates are the best depth location estimates in our method.
When applied to synthetic data, our method yielded good results if the bodies
produce weak- and mid-interfering anomalies. A test on real data over
intrusions in the Goiás Alkaline Province, Brazil, retrieved sphere-like
sources suggesting 3D bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bibtex&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;@article{melo2013,
    title = {Estimating the nature and the horizontal and vertical positions
        of 3D magnetic sources using {Euler} deconvolution},
    volume = {78},
    issn = {0016-8033, 1942-2156},
    doi = {10.1190/geo2012-0515.1},
    number = {6},
    journal = {GEOPHYSICS},
    author = {Melo, Felipe F. and Barbosa, Valeria C. F. and Uieda,
        Leonardo and Oliveira, Vanderlei C. and Silva, João B. C.},
    month = oct,
    year = {2013},
    pages = {J87--J98}
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry></feed>