<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PINGA lab</title><link href="http://pinga-lab.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://pinga-lab.github.io/feeds/oliveira-jr-v-c-v-c-f-barbosa-and-l-uieda.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://pinga-lab.github.io/</id><updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00-02:00</updated><entry><title>Polynomial equivalent layer</title><link href="http://pinga-lab.github.io/papers/paper-polynomial-eqlayer-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00-02:00</updated><author><name>Oliveira Jr, V. C., V. C. F. Barbosa, and L. Uieda</name></author><id>tag:pinga-lab.github.io,2013-01-01:papers/paper-polynomial-eqlayer-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have developed a new cost-effective method for processing
large-potential-field data sets via the equivalent-layer technique. In this
approach, the equivalent layer is divided into a regular grid of
equivalent-source windows. Inside each window, the physical-property
distribution is described by a bivariate polynomial. Hence, the
physical-property distribution within the equivalent layer is assumed to be a
piecewise polynomial function defined on a set of equivalent-source windows. We
perform any linear transformation of a large set of data as follows. First, we
estimate the polynomial coefficients of all equivalent-source windows by using
a linear regularized inversion. Second, we transform the estimated polynomial
coefficients of all windows into the physical-property distribution within the
whole equivalent layer. Finally, we premultiply this distribution by the matrix
of Green’s functions associated with the desired transformation to obtain the
transformed data. The regularized inversion deals with a linear system of
equations with dimensions based on the total number of polynomial coefficients
within all equivalent-source windows. This contrasts with the classical
approach of directly estimating the physical-property distribution within the
equivalent layer, which leads to a system based on the number of data. Because
the number of data is much larger than the number of polynomial coefficients,
the proposed polynomial representation of the physical-property distribution
within an equivalent layer drastically reduces the number of parameters to be
estimated. By comparing the total number of floating-point operations required
to estimate an equivalent layer via our method with the classical approach,
both formulated with Cholesky’s decomposition, we can verify that the
computation time required for building the linear system and for solving the
linear inverse problem can be reduced by as many as three and four orders of
magnitude, respectively. Applications to synthetic and real data show that our
method performs the standard linear transformations of potential-field data
accurately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bibtex&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;@article{oliveira2013,
    title = {Polynomial equivalent layer},
    volume = {78},
    issn = {0016-8033, 1942-2156},
    doi = {10.1190/geo2012-0196.1},
    number = {1},
    journal = {GEOPHYSICS},
    author = {Oliveira Jr., Vanderlei C. and Barbosa, Valéria C. F. and
        Uieda, Leonardo},
    month = jan,
    year = {2013},
    pages = {G1--G13},
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary></entry></feed>